<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="https://www.hpc-carpentry.org/assets/xslt/rss.xslt" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="https://www.hpc-carpentry.org/assets/css/rss.css" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>HPC Carpentry</title>
		<description>HPC Carpentry is a set of teaching materials designed to help new users take advantage of high-performance computing systems. No prior computational experience is required - these lessons are ideal for either an in-person workshop or independent study.</description>
		<link>https://www.hpc-carpentry.org/</link>
		<atom:link href="https://www.hpc-carpentry.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>The BoF at SC21</title>
				<link>https://www.hpc-carpentry.org/blog/2021/12/sc21-summary.html</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-bof-at-sc21&quot;&gt;The BoF at SC21&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The HPC Carpentry team hosted a “Birds of a Feather” session
at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://sc21.supercomputing.org/&quot;&gt;SC21&lt;/a&gt; conference.  This was a hybrid conference,
and the BoF sessions were done via Zoom, with Q&amp;amp;A done via the
Sli.do tool.  Andrew Reid was on-site and hosted the on-site
portion from the podium, while Trevor Keller, Annajiat Alim
Rasel, Alan O’Cais, and Wirawan Purwanto were on-line,
monitoring the Zoom and Sli.do questions and keeping the
session flowing for all participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The primary purpose of this was to try to reconnect with the
HPC user community, and gather feedback and guidance on how to
prioritize our efforts moving forward. The BoF was a success
on all counts: 20 people attended in-person in St. Louis, and
40 people attended via Zoom, with good, sometimes vibrant
participation from both “factions” 😇 in the Q&amp;amp;A.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We imagine that the SC21 audience is probably somewhat more
performance- and hardware-aware than the Carpentries community
at large, and possibly also biased towards facility operators,
rather than novice users.  The feedback we gained is clearly
valuable;  nevertheless, we need to keep this intrinsic bias in
mind while we evaluate and act on this input.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a number of survey questions planned in advance,
which were presented via the polling functionality in the
Sli.do.  This information was captured and is available
in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hpc-carpentry/coordination/tree/main/conferences/SC21&quot;&gt;coordination repo&lt;/a&gt;.
The principal results are that attendees would like to see,
in descending order of preference:
Future lessons on containers;  Python and MPI;  Dask and
Julia;  Ability to mix and match lesson content;
Constructing half-day lessons that use the templating
capability to adapting lessons to permanent on-premise
facilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the planned polling questions were done, a more general
discussion ensued, largely captured in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://codimd.carpentries.org/9-Y8OaVIT2qpb_P47TR7Lw&quot;&gt;CodiMD&lt;/a&gt;
document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A number of attendees were interested in how to give feedback
on their experience with the lessons, and seemed uncertain what
feedback we’re looking for.  The answer is that we are mainly
looking for actionable feedback¹ that helps improve the lessons
for the community.  The main mechanism by which we imagine this
happening is through instructor and learner comments via poll
(to be written), Slack, and GitHub issues.  At the end of the
lesson, following usual Carpentries practice, organizers
should ask learners for positive and negative feedback, on
green or red sticky notes, and conduct a post-workshop survey.
This info, particularly the red stickies, is what we’re
looking for, and ideally would be translated into issues on
the appropriate lesson repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will be digesting the feedback received over the next few
weeks, and look forward to working through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hpc-carpentry/coordination/milestone/1&quot;&gt;generated
issues&lt;/a&gt; over the coming months to ensure our
lessons benefit from this excellent community participation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;highlights&quot;&gt;Highlights&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One way HPC Carpentry can add value, beyond the lessons
themselves, is as a clearing house for HPC educational
resources generally.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The lessons and resources we choose to focus on are a
signal to the community about our priorities, so we 
should take some care in selecting these.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MPI, implemented with low-level programming languages 
(C, C++, Fortran), is still the most commonly-used framework 
for parallel programming.  It’s appropriate for 
HPC Carpentry to develop lessons that focus on this 
foundational material.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New users are increasingly unfamiliar with the command line
and file system hierarchy. Extra instructional effort may be
needed to help bridge this gap, including the effort of 
developing GUI-focused lessons based on Open OnDemand 
or JupyterHub.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some users still struggle with the difference in character
between distributed and shared HPC resources, and more familiar
laptop or workstation resources.  HPC is not just a big
laptop.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Interest in cloud-based HPC resources is surprisingly high, 
driven by people with possibly-transient HPC workloads but without
institutional HPC facilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Actionable feedback” may seem flip, but we mean it
sincerely: comments that include some tangible suggestion
for improvement are tremendously helpful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;!-- links --&gt;

</description>
				<author>Andrew Reid</author>
				
				<category> Community </category><category> Lesson development </category>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hpc-carpentry.org/blog/2021/12/sc21-summary.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Applying lesson development design principles</title>
				<link>https://www.hpc-carpentry.org/blog/2020/11/hpccarpentry-lesson-development.html</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-workshop-with-coderefinery&quot;&gt;A Workshop with CodeRefinery&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Together with CodeRefinery (&lt;a href=&quot;https://coderefinery.org/&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;), we helped to organise
a variant of an instructor training workshop for the
EU HPC Centres of Excellence (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hpccoe.eu/&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;) with a clear focus on HPC
related material and teaching. We discussed lesson design a number
of times during this workshop. This blog post is about a few interesting
things we realised during those discussions -
most notably using Bloom’s Taxonomy to formulate learning objectives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The motivation to look at this was mostly spurred by Greg Wilson’s
great book, “Teaching Tech together”, (&lt;a href=&quot;https://teachtogether.tech/en/index.html&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;).
&lt;a href=&quot;https://teachtogether.tech/en/index.html#s:process-objectives&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt;, Greg
defines:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Objectives vs. Outcomes&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;A learning objective is what a lesson strives to achieve. A learning outcome
is what it actually achieves, i.e. what learners actually take away. The role
of summative assessment is therefore to compare learning outcomes with learning
objectives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we want to describe what we want to teach and what we want our learners
to pick up. Typically, each Carpentries’ episode encodes this in the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;yaml&lt;/code&gt;
frontmatter part of every lesson episode. For example, the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/swcarpentry/shell-novice&quot;&gt;shell-novice&lt;/a&gt; defines the
following objectives for the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/swcarpentry/shell-novice/gh-pages/_episodes/02-filedir.md&quot;&gt;lesson module “Navigating Files and Directories”&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;objectives:
- &quot;Explain the similarities and differences between a file and a directory.&quot;
- &quot;Translate an absolute path into a relative path and vice versa.&quot;
- &quot;Construct absolute and relative paths that identify specific files and directories.&quot;
- &quot;Use options and arguments to change the behaviour of a shell command&quot;
- &quot;Demonstrate the use of tab completion, and explain its advantages.&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-guide-to-formulating-learning-objectives&quot;&gt;A guide to formulating learning objectives&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://teachtogether.tech/en/index.html#s:process-objectives&quot;&gt;Bloom’s taxonomy and other taxonomies&lt;/a&gt;
offer a structure or guideline, to help a lesson designer and teacher to formulate
these learning objectives. Bloom’s taxonomy itself comprises of 6 concepts which can
be paired with verbs that help guide the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remembering:&lt;/strong&gt; Exhibit memory of previously learned material by recalling facts,
terms, basic concepts, and answers. (recognize, list, describe, name, find)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Understanding:&lt;/strong&gt; Demonstrate understanding of facts and ideas by organizing,
comparing, translating, interpreting, giving descriptions, and stating main ideas.
(interpret, summarize, paraphrase, classify, explain)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Applying:&lt;/strong&gt; Solve new problems by applying acquired knowledge, facts, techniques
and rules in a different way. (build, identify, use, plan, select)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Analyzing:&lt;/strong&gt; Examine and break information into parts by identifying motives or
causes; make inferences and find evidence to support generalizations. (compare,
contrast, simplify)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evaluating:&lt;/strong&gt; Present and defend opinions by making judgments about information,
validity of ideas, or quality of work based on a set of criteria. (check, choose,
critique, prove, rate)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creating:&lt;/strong&gt; Compile information together in a different way by combining elements
in a new pattern or proposing alternative solutions. (design, construct, improve,
adapt, maximize, solve)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-hpc-inspired-exercise&quot;&gt;An HPC inspired exercise&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the aforementioned workshop, I (Peter) asked all participants to imagine
they want
to teach learners about &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;scp&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ssh&lt;/code&gt; (participants were able to choose). The
workshop participants were split in teams and asked to  formulate learning
objectives guided by Bloom’s Taxonomy for the topic they chose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a teacher, I expected the native English speakers to complete this
task with ease and the non-native speakers to struggle. The following is directly
copied from the workshops HackMD pad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h3 id=&quot;remembering&quot;&gt;Remembering&lt;/h3&gt;

  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;ssh: name the command and list it’s parameters&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;scp: Name the basic structure of a scp call: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;command source destination&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;ssh: Can the student explain what does the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ssh&lt;/code&gt; acronym stand for?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;h3 id=&quot;understanding&quot;&gt;Understanding&lt;/h3&gt;

  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;ssh: explain what the command does&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;scp: Paraphrase the similarity of SCP to CP - across physical limits of computers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;h3 id=&quot;applying&quot;&gt;Applying&lt;/h3&gt;

  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;ssh: use the command to log in to a new cluster / server&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;scp: Use SCP to transfer a set of files or folders&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;h3 id=&quot;analyzing&quot;&gt;Analyzing&lt;/h3&gt;

  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;ssh: compare the local environment to the remote environment (to contrast source and destination machine)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;scp: Compare : compare to rsync and ability to know when to to use which (simplify this!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;h3 id=&quot;evaluating&quot;&gt;Evaluating&lt;/h3&gt;

  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;scp: Rate approaches to share scientific data (cloud versus shared folder on parallel filesystem versus central [ftp] server)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;ssh: choose whether to use ssh to do a given task&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;h3 id=&quot;creating&quot;&gt;Creating&lt;/h3&gt;

  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;ssh: solve a security problem using ssh&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;scp: Design an approach to share scientific data to more than 3 destinations (on a daily basis).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;ssh: Can the student modify the following ssh command to be able to log-in directly into the directory /home/dir1?: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ssh username@login.hpc.xxx.xx.uk&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-use-blooms-taxonomy&quot;&gt;How to use “Bloom’s Taxonomy”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It looked like all participants struggled with this task irrespective of
their English speaking capabilities. Learners asked me how I would approach
this and I provided two hints:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Categories in Bloom’s taxonomy build upon each other. Take this prioritised
list: Remembering, Understanding, Applying, Analyzing, Evaluating, Creating.
If learners don’t remember the content that was taught, it will be hard for
them to exhibit understanding. For learners to apply content, e.g. to new
examples or domains, they first need to understand the content taught. I told
my participants that I try to balance these categories mostly by the context
of the course I am designing. For example, in the context of carpentries’
workshops, the volume to teach is often quite large and the time to dive into
details is hardly ever available. Hence, I would limit myself to “Remembering,
Understanding, Applying” for designing and organising my lessons. Anything in
the higher categories, “Analyzing, Evaluating, Creating” I often consider a
bonus.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I typically judge my formulation of learning objects by how amenable they are
to create assessments from. In other words, a learning objective in the
very first category of the taxonomy &lt;strong&gt;Remember&lt;/strong&gt; like “At the end of this
module, learners remember how to use SCP.” is way too broad of a formulation
to help guide me in creating lessons and produce tangible assessments. I’d
rather suggest to put it like so: “At the end of this module, learners
recognize the use of scp for transferring single files or entire folders.”
This formulation lends itself to create two assessments or exercises.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-testimony-of-a-participant&quot;&gt;A testimony of a participant&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me (Alan), I realised that I had never really considered Bloom’s taxonomy
beyond an abstract sense. When it was time to leverage it during the exercise
to set lesson objectives, I struggled to apply it in a practical way. It raised
questions for me about what level(s) of the taxonomy we are supposed to target
in lesson episodes. After the workshop, and for this blogpost, I read up on this
a little and came across a post from the University of Arkansas (&lt;a href=&quot;https://tips.uark.edu/using-blooms-taxonomy/&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;)
that helped me to grasp the key points in the use of the taxonomy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You set Lesson Objectives for the overall lesson that target a particular level of
the taxonomy. For HPC Carpentry, this is most likely the “Applying” level.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In your lesson episodes you should follow the principle (trivially adapted from (&lt;a href=&quot;https://teachtogether.tech/en/index.html&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;))
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Use Bloom’s Taxonomy to make sure that the verbs you choose for your (episode)
level objectives build up to the level of the verb that is in the (lesson) level
objective. The (episode) level verbs can be below or equal to the (lesson) level
verb, but they CANNOT be higher in level. For example, your (lesson) level verb
might be an Applying level verb, “illustrate.” Your (episode) level verbs can be
from any Bloom’s level that is equal or below this level (applying,
understanding, or remembering).&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-summary-and-a-request&quot;&gt;A summary and a request&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bloom’s taxonomy appears high level at first sight. Once you sit down and try to
employ it, a lesson designer can be guided by their use to more effectively and
better formulate learning goals. The resulting goals are expected to offer more
tangible guidance once you design the teaching material in question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you feel about Bloom’s taxonomy and how we put it to use for creating
learning goals for &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;scp&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ssh&lt;/code&gt;? Feel free to leave a comment below or join
the discussion on the HPC Carpentry Slack channel (&lt;a href=&quot;https://swcarpentry.slack.com/archives/CEXAZR52T&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;) (to access the channel
you first need to 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://swc-slack-invite.herokuapp.com/&quot;&gt;join the Carpentries Slack organisation&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<author>Alan O'Cais, Peter Steinbach</author>
				
				<category> Community </category><category> Lesson development </category>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hpc-carpentry.org/blog/2020/11/hpccarpentry-lesson-development.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>HPC Carpentry Task Force</title>
				<link>https://www.hpc-carpentry.org/blog/2020/09/task-force.html</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;In the fall of 2020, following successful engagement at the 
Carpentries@Home conference, a number of HPC Carpentry contributors got 
together and formed an “HPC Carpentry Task Force”, with an expected
lifetime of about three months, with the goal of identifying and solving
the issues which stand between the current state of the lesson,
and incorporating our material into the mainstream Carpentries
infrastructure, though the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/carpentries-incubator/proposals&quot;&gt;incubator&lt;/a&gt; mechanism&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An &lt;a href=&quot;https://codimd.carpentries.org/ct7yfc_LSseoC8mEmbVEiQ?both&quot;&gt;initial meeting&lt;/a&gt; was held on Sept. 16, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving forward, the plan is to coordinate several co-working
sessions where volunteers can identify and clear remaining
issues with the various repositories, and also to have 
higher-level coordination meetings, approximately monthly,
where issue priorities can be discussed, and tasks requiring
higher-level coordination can be undertaken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discussion and coordination takes place on the 
HPC Carpentry &lt;a href=&quot;https://swcarpentry.slack.com&quot;&gt;Slack channel&lt;/a&gt;, The Carpentries’ HPC
&lt;a href=&quot;https://carpentries.topicbox.com/groups/discuss-hpc&quot;&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt;, and through issues on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hpc-carpentry/coordination&quot;&gt;coordination&lt;/a&gt;
repository on Github.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All are welcome!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<author>Andrew Reid</author>
				
				<category> Community </category>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hpc-carpentry.org/blog/2020/09/task-force.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>HPC Carpentry at CarpentryCon @ Home 2020</title>
				<link>https://www.hpc-carpentry.org/blog/2020/07/hpccarpentry-at-carpentrycon-at-home.html</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Some of the HPC Carpentry team are very keen to bring HPC Carpentry into the carpentries as an
incubator project
(&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/carpentries-incubator/proposals&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;) and eventually become a member of the Carpentries (or the Carpentry Lab (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/carpentrieslab/proposals&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;) at least). To start
this, they’ve proposed a breakout
session for carpentrycon at home (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/carpentrycon/carpentryconhome-proposals/issues/33&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;) which will take place on July 20,
2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides sampling the community for expectations and hopes, we would love to propose a way forward
to bring the community
together and focus on hpc-intro (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hpc-carpentry/hpc-intro&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;). Key points of this are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;propose a github manager who will coordinate reviews, reviewers and issues&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;propose building a set of task forces to tackle particular issues, and asking for volunteers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;suggest to hold co-working hours (biweekly for 60-90 minutes via zoom) to establish continuous
work on the material&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this message, we call for volunteers to help shape the session (we need at least 2 more people
since we plan to have 4
breakout rooms during the session). Please step forward and reply to the open issue in our repo
connected to the proposal (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hpc-carpentry/hpc-intro/issues/123&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;) or to the proposal itself (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/carpentrycon/carpentryconhome-proposals/issues/33&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;) or email us at
&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:maintainers-hpc@lists.carpentries.org&quot;&gt;maintainers-hpc@lists.carpentries.org&lt;/a&gt; (can you feel how keen we are to get you involved!).&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<author>Alan O'Cais, Peter Steinbach</author>
				
				<category> Community </category>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hpc-carpentry.org/blog/2020/07/hpccarpentry-at-carpentrycon-at-home.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
